these days everyone is using an AI IDE
like wind surf or cursor even non-coders
to do some incredible things I feel like
the king of productivity when I use
these tools especially with some of the
recent additions like documentation
retrieval and Claude mCP support the
problem is even though there are a lot
of strengths with these tools there are
just as many flaws I mean they
hallucinate awful code all of the time
even when you give them extensive
documentation and instructions ladies
and Gent gentlemen it is long overdue
that we get a big upgrade for these AI
coding assistants to tackle all of these
hallucination problems and I think I've
started to uncover what the next
Evolution will be for this and I'm not
just talking about incremental
improvements I talking about a complete
Paradigm Shift what I'm about to show
you is very very experimental but I
truly believe it's going to be the next
wave of innovation for AI coding and it
all revolves around specialized sub
agents and clouds mCP and I'm going to
demonstrate it for you in this video
using archon as an example which is the
AI agent that I started recently that
builds other AI agents using pantic Ai
and Lang graph my two favorite
Frameworks now buckle up and just hear
me out on this cuz I'm going to get you
on the same page as fast as I possibly
can the problem right now is AI coding
assistants are too General they're the
Jack of all trades but also the master
of none when it comes to coding with
different Frameworks tools and libraries
it doesn't doesn't matter if you give
them the documentation for something
like a framework that is not enough
they're still too General and so that
begs the question what's the solution
how do we get more specialized here is
the golden ticket that I've started to
dream about that I want to share with
you in this video imagine having
specialized agents that are created
specifically to code with a certain tool
or framework and these agents can be
called upon by the general AI coders
like wind surf or cursor when necessary
it's the best of both because sometimes
you need that General coder and then
other times you need something that
knows how to work with the specific
framework that you are trying to code
with and this is possible right now
because you can Define these specialized
agents as sub agents that work as mCP
tools that you can bake into all the
popular AI coding assistants because
claud's mCP is becoming so widely
adopted now sound complicated it's
actually not and I'll show you exactly
how to do it in this video we'll take
archon my AI agent build that I
mentioned earlier and turn it into one
of these mCP sub agents and then bake it
right into wind Surf and you could do
this with cursor or any other AI coder
so allow me to demonstrate this for you
I can guarantee that even though this is
very experimental in Alpha it is going
to light up your imagination with the
Limitless possibilities that we have
here so we're going to dive right into a
demo of using archon within wind surf to
build us an AI agent and then for the
rest of this video I'll show you exactly
how I set it up cuz archon originally
just started running in a streamlet
interface and I actually show you
exactly how I built archon in this video
you can check out right here using L
graph and pantic Ai and now we're
focusing on the next evolution of archon
turning it into a sub agent with mCP
right here so let's go ahead and give it
our first prompt and so right here I'm
saying build me an AI agent using archon
that is able to search the web using
Brave so just starting with a very basic
prompt because archon is still in its
infancy here but if you click on the
hammer icon here we'll actually check
this out before we send in the prompt I
have my mCP servers here which archon is
the only one that I have configured at
this point we've got two tools we have
one to create the thread ID because
archon needs some sort of conversation
ID to manage the conversation just like
wind surf does and then we have our
primary tool to actually invoke the
creation of the agent or to work on it
if iteratively with that human in the
loop feedback loop that I showed in my
first video for archon so those are our
two tools let's go ahead and send in
this request so the first thing it'll do
is call this tool to create our thread
ID which is now going to pass into
archon for all future calls and so it's
going to be using this API endpoint that
I created for archon um since that first
video as well and so it's making that
first request already you can see that
wind surf is waiting for the API request
to finish and this will take a little
bit cuz archon has that full workflow
where it goes through the Reasoner model
create that initial scope for the agent
and then it goes to the coder agent like
we see right here that performs rag to
get the pantic AI documentation combines
it all together to create that initial
version of our AI agent and then the
control is going to get passed back to
winds surf in a little bit here once it
finished creating the agent so by the
way this is using 03 mini for the
Reasoner model right now and then GPT 40
for the actual coder and then look at
that we finished our API response right
here um for our archon API and now all
the code is passed to Wi to then
actually create these files for us so
look at how seamless that is it the
control just operates so well going
between the different agents that we
have here and there we go it used the
code from archon to build us agent. py
and then just like we have archon build
out the requirements. text file and then
the tools file and the em. example file
it's spitting out all of these because
wind surf is really relying on archon
here to directed as the specialized sub
agent for building pantic AI agents and
I'm not going to actually show running
this right now but I will show at the
end of this video a full example of
building out an agent perfecting it and
actually running it and testing it but
yeah look at this like was looking at
this right here overall the code looks
good like we got our agent right here
the requirements look good the agent
tool for executing the brave search
looks good we got our EMV example file
with the brave API key this is looking
absolutely perfect just so cool and and
I hope you can see that like even though
this is a very basic example at this
point with both the infancy of archon
and how basic this agent is I hope you
can see that you could make so many
different kinds of specialized sub
agents that you have something like wind
surf or cursor call into when necessary
and the way that you can tell these AI
coders when to use these is just in the
description for these tools like I can
tell it like when you want to build a
pantic Ai and L graph agent then use
archon here are your tools for it and so
you have all these descriptions to guide
it without having to actually even edit
the cursor config or edit the rules for
wind surf you just have it all defined
right here in your mCP servers so with
any new innovation always comes a lot of
questions and I'm sure that you have a
couple on this as well so let me know in
the comments if there's something I
don't cover in this video but I'm going
to try to address a couple of the big
ones that I'm sure will come up right
now I mean the first big question is why
not just use the documentation feature
built right into AI coders like wind
surf or cursor I can literally go into
the bottom right here say at pantic Ai
and then boom I have the pantic AI
documentation available which wind surf
is going to use to fulfill my next
request and I can do at L graph and then
boom I've got the L graph docs as well
so why not just use this to code my
pedantic Ai and L graph agents instead
of using archon and there's two primary
reasons for this first of all with the
whole agentic flow that we have for
archon having the Reasoner model and the
system prompts that we have built in we
get this very consistent output for the
different files that we split our agent
into and just the structure for things
in the scripts themselves and we don't
get that with wi Sur for cursor you can
try to kind of edit the rules and stuff
but really it's more than just the
system prompt it's the whole flow of
archon that produces this very
consistent code I like that a lot and I
don't get that with windsurf it produces
code that looks very different every
single time and that produces some more
errors as well and that's kind of the
second big thing as well is that the
code is always going to be better with
Aron and it might be kind of comparable
at this point because archon is in its
infancy but as we build it out and add
self feedback loops the ability to break
things up into different sections as
it's building and really split the
problem into small steps it's going to
be so much more robust than just having
a general coder spew out all the code at
once and then improve on it from there
it's just going to be more of a one shot
and then just make it more robust you're
just going to have such a better
starting point using something like
archon and the way that it can leverage
the documentation better as well so
that's why we care about using archon
and then the second big question is why
are we generating This Thread ID here I
mean it's kind of weird like mCP servers
are supposed to be stateless right like
you call the tool and then the tool
gives you a response then forgets
everything but in this case archon is a
sub agent tool that actually maintains
the conversation history just like winds
surf does here's the Lang graph graph
that we have for archon and all of this
like this is stateful we have the
Reasoner that creates the scope and that
goes to the coder agent and then we have
this human in the loop where we can
actually ask it to iterate on the agent
so it has to maintain the conversation
using some sort of identifier to know
that this wind surf conversation maps to
this run of archon that is iterating on
an agent and so we have this thread ID
that it creates and the llm has to
remember to pass that in to the tool so
it has to keep track of this thread ID
which is a little bit uncomfortable that
we rely on the llm for that but this has
actually worked 100 % of the time for me
surprisingly and so then in any future
iteration where we maybe tell it to use
archon again to improve the agent in
some way it'll then use the same thread
ID so that it's invoking that execution
of archon going on to kind of that next
step in the human in the loop feedback
loop that we have here that's how I use
the thread ID again kind of forced a
little bit into mCP but it works pretty
well and so yeah I'm kind of at the
Forefront of innovation like I haven't
seen anything like this and so
definitely trying to just figure
everything out as I go right here but
getting some really cool results and so
with that let's dive into mCP a little
bit talk about archon and I'll show you
how I brought everything together the
sponsor of today's video is fish audio
an extremely impressive voice cloning
and voiceover solution that is
transforming the way that developers
marketers and content creators create
audio with AI and fish audio is not just
another speech to text tool it is a
state-ofthe-art realtime speech to
speech model that delivers top tier
realism let me show you a demo really
quick now from the fish audio homepage
you just go to my voice Library custom
voice and then build a new voice and
this is where you can clone yourself in
just minutes you add in your cover image
name and description then at the bottom
here is where you add in your sample
clips for it to mimic you recommended
around 30 seconds and you can even
record yourself right here in the UI so
they make it very easy for you so go
ahead and click on create in my case I'm
just going to use the custom voice that
I already have built here I'll paste in
my kind of silly sample prompt I have
here saying archon is the best best AI
agent Builder also a pro tip you can
change the spelling of things a little
bit just to help it enunciate better and
all of this is accessible through their
API as well if you want to use it
programmatically so you can change the
speed and volume as well and then click
on Create and then just a few seconds
it'll generate our audio clip and play
it for us archon is the best AI agent
Builder that ever was and ever will be
don't believe me well why wouldn't you
fish audio is designed to do it all
YouTube voiceovers voice agents adding
multiple languages to your projects you
name it and at the same time it is super
affordable 50% cheaper and two times
faster than 11 Labs which has been the
go-to voice platform for a while now
even though it's always felt very
overpriced to me so it definitely seems
like fish audio could be taking the
crown as the go-to AI voice platform to
say I'm impressed while testing out fish
audio is saying the least if you are
ready to level up your AI voice game and
make your project sound truly
professional head on over to f fish.
audio sign up for their generous free
trial and experience the magic of their
AI voice cloning for yourself I mean you
can literally try it out in under 2
minutes so definitely give it a go see
how well it works for you and I'll have
a link in the description to fish audio
as well so the most important thing for
me to start with as I show you how I
built archon into an mCP sub agent is to
give you some context around what mCP is
what archon is and how I can combine
them together to build this very
specialized agent so first of all mCP it
is a protocol developed by Claude pretty
recently here just a few months ago to
standardize the use of tools with large
language models so they have this full
article that you can read if you are
curious but essentially it's a way where
you can create these servers that you
spin up that have access to API
endpoints for a certain service like
GitHub Google Drive Discord whatever it
might be and so essentially This Server
is exposed to a large language model to
give those tools dynamically to an l M
so when you spin up an mCP server for
GitHub and then give it to your llm in
Wind surf or claw desktop or whatever
the llm can now do things on your behalf
in your GitHub repositories it is so
cool how fast you can spin up these
servers and then instantly give llms
access to do all these things for you
there's a server for brave search
there's one for Google Drive for your
SQL databases there's all these third
party servers that are created by the
community kind of like archon is going
to be now so you can do things uh with
the jet brains or stripe or you got AWS
S3 uh if I scroll down a little bit
we've got Discord deep seek R1 all of
these are servers that we can download
right now they're all open source I can
run them on my computer or reference
some API endpoint in the cloud and then
boom all those tools will now be
available for my llm wherever I'm
running it and so that's what we're
doing with arcom so arcom is an AI meta
agent it is an agent that builds other
agents using pantic Ai and L graph so
I've been building it out started very
recently I only have one video on my
channel on it so far but essentially I'm
developing an inations to teach pantic
Ai and L graph and then also eventually
to build it into a very robust sub agent
that we can use in AI coders to build
these agents with pantic AI L graph very
very nicely and so what I'm doing right
now with mCP is turning it into a tool
that we can give to llms like we just
saw we did in Wind surf so essentially
claw 3.5 Sonet running in Wind surf has
archon as a tool and so this is the Lang
graph graph that defines the full
workflow for coding agents with archon
so we have the Reasoner at the start
that kind of defines the scope for
building the agent and the high level
reasoning and that goes into our faster
coder agent which actually produces the
code and then we have this feedback loop
right here getting input from you as the
user so it can iterate on the agent and
then it gives the final response and
instructions to run the agent at the end
and so we package this entire workflow
together to give as a tool to AI coders
that is the power of using archon as an
mCP sub agent and so now kind of with
that as our context here I'll actually
dive into how I set up the mCP server
and hooked up everything with archon so
this is the python script for our archon
mCP server I'm going to go over it at a
high level right now might do a future
video on my channel where I really dive
into building a python mCP server from
scratch but also I'll have the links to
the documentation in the description if
you're curious to dive into that
yourself you can make servers for both
Python and JavaScript so at a high level
here we're using fast API with the mCP
python SDK we have our first tool right
here to create that thread ID again
because archon needs that to manage the
conversation history and then we have
our second tool to actually invoke
archon itself and the way that we do
that is through an API endpoint that I
created for archon so this is new to
version three of archon as well we have
this fast API endpoint that I created um
that is interacting with archon in a
very similar way to how we did with
streamlit in the last video on archon on
my channel and then the graph for archon
that I showed in the last video how to
build completely from scratch this
remains entirely the same so there's
nothing that I Chang in here we're just
wrapping it all up in this API endpoint
with fast API that I'm then calling
right here in the mCP server so it's a
nice and simple implementation where we
don't actually have to use archon as an
mCP server now I'm remaining flexible
for you where you could still work in
streamlit or use this as an API endpoint
and some other front end that you make
for archon you don't have to use it as
an mCP server but I still make it very
easy to do so as well and so actually if
I go into the read me here let me just
open the preview for this um the updated
instructions for archon I show you
actually how to run this both without
the uh mCP server setup uh so if you
want to just do it with streamlet or
with mCP so I covered both of these I
got these instructions right here in the
REM me to set up everything very very
easily so you can play around with this
yourself in Wind Sur for cursor or
streamlet or wherever um then the other
really important thing that I want to
hit on for this mCP server the way that
it works in general these dock strings
that we Define at the top of our
function definitions this is very
similar to Tools in pantic Ai and laying
chain these actually tell the llm when
and how to use these tools so this exact
string that I see right here I'll go
back over to wind surf I'll show you
this look at that it is right here so
the definition of the function this
string right here is actually put into
the prompt for CLA 3.5 Sonet in Wind
surf so that it understands when and how
to use these tools and so I can give
Specific Instructions here like for
example telling Claud that before it can
run archon it needs to generate a thread
ID if it's the start of building
building an AI agent and then if it's
not the start needs to pass in the same
thread ID so archon is managing that
conversation cuz obviously it won't run
if there's not a thread ID yet it has to
pass that in as one of the parameters to
this tool when it runs archon so that is
the mCP server as a whole again nothing
changed with the graph very simple fast
API implementation don't need to dive
into this overall and then I also have
this neat little script that I have
created I have this in the instructions
as well but it'll completely set up your
virtual environment for you and it'll
even generate the mCP config to put into
cursor or wisor so I actually pop up my
terminal here I'll even show you that so
this is the API in point that we have
running right here but if I stop this
and I run the command
Python and then setup mCP dopy my
virtual environment is already created
so it skips that step but then look at
this it gives me my configuration that
I'd have to put into cursor instructions
for that in the readme and then it also
gives me the Json to put in the um the
config for mCP in Wind surf or something
like Claude desktop as well so you run
this script you know exactly what to do
to set up your archon mCP so I make it
as simple as I possibly can for you all
right so really quick let me show you
how to run everything then we'll build
an agent from scratch so going back to
the read me here which again is just at
the root of the GitHub repository we
have our installation instructions and
so if you're doing it the old way just
interacting through streamlet and not as
an mCP server again that is still
supported then you can follow these
commands right here so you just clone
the repo activate your virtual
environment install all your
requirements then if you're using
through mCP you can run this setup
script that I showed earlier which sets
up your virtual environment gives you
your mCP config and then you want to
activate your virtual environment as
well and then I have instructions for
both wind Surf and cursor how to include
the config that the setup mCP script
gives you and it'll be the same or at
least very similar to one of these two
if you're using something else like claw
desktop or some other AI coder that
supports mCP and then set up all your
environment variables all of this
remains unchanged same thing with
running this python script here to
actually get the pantic AI documentation
and then put it in the super base
knowledge base for Rag and then using
mCP servers you'll run the API endpoint
to expose archon as an API otherwise you
can just use streamlit directly because
that interacts right with the graph
instead of going through the API like we
do with m CP so that is everything for
running I'm not going to go through all
these commands right now um cuz I hope
it's really clear for you so I have this
all up running on my machine already so
now we're going to go ahead and actually
test it all out because now we have the
full archon graph packaged together as a
tool for wind Surf and I also want to
reemphasize like super important for you
to know that like this really is just in
the first stages of development I'm
going to add so many more nodes and
improve system prompts and add in a tool
Library like so many ideas I have to
make this really robust but even this is
a good starting point so let's go ahead
build an agent from scratch iterate on
it and test it out so I thought it would
be fitting to take the brave agent we
started at the beginning of the video
and see that through to completion for
our final demo here so I am building it
from scratch but using the same prom so
I've got the API endpoints spun up for
archon right here graphs service. I'll
show the logs for that so you can see
things happening in real time as we
build the agent so I'll paste in the
same prompt here use archon to make an
AI agent so first it gets the thread ID
now it says It'll ask archon for help I
just love that like it just shows it
like this is an agent asking another
agent for help a sub agent when it knows
it has the expertise it doesn't and so
starting with our Reasoner model 03 mini
it's creating that scope which also
includes the pantic AI documentation
Pages it thinks the coder should look at
which it goes ahead and does so pantic
AI coder performing rag getting all the
contents here to create our AI agent
based on the pantic AI documentation and
I will be expanding to work with Lang
graph later as well but just starting
very simple here with archon so now it's
generating that final response wind surf
is still waiting for it but in just a
little bit here we'll see it Flash and
then yep there we go all right so now we
got the final response from archon and
it's going to take those files and
Implement them into my IDE here so
starting with the requirement. text okay
looks pretty good pantic Ai and httpx
definitely only dependencies that we do
need here and then we have our agent
okay that looks pretty pretty good it
says the model is none which I don't
like that so it looks like it's pretty
good overall I mean the brave Search
tool looks good okay like that and then
we have our envi example file for the
brave API key looks good looks like
we'll have to implement an llm here but
everything else looks good so I'm going
to accept these changes but now I'm
going to use human in the loop because I
want to let me actually move myself here
so you can see me typing right here I'm
going to ask it to fix the first big
issue that I see here because model is
none so I'm going to say ask archon to
fix the model for the brave search agent
right now the model is none and I want
to use GPT we'll just say GPT 40 so now
it's going to use that human in the loop
here and so it's going to invoke archon
using the exact same thread ID so now
going back over to the logs here it
jumps right to the uh yeah right right
to the pantic AI coder so it didn't
invoke the Reasoner this time because we
are already within the graph execution
within that loop with just the coder
agent so we got the response back from
Aron and now it edited the model so open
AI GPT 4 and it should probably be GPT
40 so I'll just go ahead and edit this
right here you still want a little bit
of human intervention especially because
archon is such a new implementation at
this point but still really cool we
could see there that it actually use
archon to then update the agent and
obviously this is something that that
wind surf probably could have done
itself but I just wanted to give it
really simple example here for human in
the loop with Aron and so yeah this is
looking pretty good what I'm going to do
right here is test this off camera fix
up any little glitches that I have here
and then we'll go ahead and run this
with a streamlit interface so I'm back
after fixing just a couple of things it
did not take much to get this to a
working State and I'll even show in a
streamlet interface that I made really
quick for this agent everything working
perfectly so the main thing that I had
to fix obviously besides getting
everything with the environment variable
set up cuz I had to create a EnV and
then it wasn't using that in my agent is
it didn't really have the right URLs and
parameters for interacting with the
brave API so in the end it didn't
actually mess up with things related to
pantic AI or Lan graph it was a
hallucination with the brave API which I
didn't give the documentation for so
can't really blame archon it would have
been the exact same thing with wind surf
that's why a tool library is going to be
so useful so I could have like a
pre-made Brave tool that it would just
pull and use right there for the pantic
AI agent so that's all I had to fix up
everything else I kept exactly the same
and so then I created the streamlet
interface that I just ran right here
with command streamlet run and then
streamlet ui. piy obviously added that
as dependency for the project as well
and then boom we now have this chat
interface right here for our agent that
was almost completely generated by
archon with wind surf just calling it
for the help to make this agent so I can
ask it a question like what is the net
worth of Elon Musk the kind of thing an
llm wouldn't know by itself because of
its training cut off so it's going to be
leveraging the web search tool here
which it did you can see right here in
the logs that it made the request to the
brave API for his net worth and there we
go $400 billion which is absolutely
insane but the right answer so there we
go our archon agent is working perfectly
and we're just going to keep building
out archon as an mCP server doing some
crazy things with it it's going to just
keep getting better and better now that
archon can be integrated into AI idees
as an mCP server I have so many ideas to
turn this into a massively powerful sub
agent to create other agents with my
favorite Frameworks I just love that I
can run wild with the agentic flow for
archon and not have to worry about the
logistics of having to actually create
and edit files because the AI coders
just take care of that for me now so
check the GitHub readme that I have
Linked In the description for all the
future plans that I have for archon or
at least some of them I mean I've got so
many ideas in my head I've got things
like self feedback loops or breaking
down the agent creation down into
smaller steps a tool Library so many
insane ideas and if you have more
suggestions yourself or if you want to
contribute definitely feel free because
archon is a community-driven project so
if you appreciate this video and you're
looking forward to more things AI agents
and archon I would really appreciate a
like and a subscribe and with that I
will see you in the next video